<prompt>
  <task>
    <objective>Transform a panel-style podcast transcript (3+ speakers) into a coherent, multi-voice narrative while removing commercial content and audience-retention devices</objective>
    <core_principle>Preserve the unique conversational architecture of panel discussions—overlapping voices, collaborative thinking, group dynamics—while eliminating filler, commercial interruptions, and preview content. Elevate readability to professional transcript standards without sacrificing the authentic texture of group conversation.</core_principle>
  </task>

  <scope>
    <preserve>
      - Each speaker's distinctive voice, vocabulary, and rhetorical signature
      - Panel dynamics: how speakers build on, challenge, or redirect each other
      - Group conversational rhythms (fast-paced exchanges, contemplative moments)
      - Role differentiation (host steering, guests contributing, co-hosts mediating)
      - Multi-party disagreements and alliance formation
      - Collaborative idea development across speakers
      - Group humor, shared references, and in-jokes
      - Meta-commentary about the panel itself ("we're all talking over each other")
      - Substantive interruptions that advance discussion
      - How consensus emerges (or doesn't) through group exchange
      - Individual speech patterns and how they contrast with others
      - Moments of simultaneous agreement or collective realization
      - Topic hand-offs and conversational threading between multiple speakers
    </preserve>
    
    <remove>
      - ALL preview and teaser content (see dedicated section below)
      - ALL advertising content and sponsorship reads
      - Product promotions, discount codes, affiliate links
      - Patreon/subscription pitches, merchandise promotions
      - "Word from our sponsor" segments
      - Call-to-action requests (subscribe, follow, like)
      - Self-promotional content (upcoming tour dates, book plugs, unless central to discussion)
      - Filler words per speaker: "um," "uh," "like," "you know," "so," "basically"
      - Verbal tics and individual disfluencies
      - Conversational fillers: "right?", "I mean", "at the end of the day"
      - Empty affirmations ("yeah," "mm-hmm") unless signaling genuine contribution
      - Decorative cross-talk that obscures rather than reveals
      - Background noise references, audio technical issues
      - Excessive hedging when it adds no epistemic value
    </remove>
    
    <handle_carefully>
      - Multi-speaker interruptions: Keep if revealing dynamics; trim if creating confusion
      - Overlapping agreement: Preserve when showing collective momentum; consolidate if repetitive
      - Tangents: Keep if showing panel's exploratory chemistry; trim if purely social
      - Repetition across speakers: Keep if building consensus or showing disagreement; consolidate if redundant
      - Group laughter: Note in narration if tone-significant; omit if decorative
      - Side conversations: Keep if substantive; remove if fragmenting main thread
      - Host interjections: Keep if steering usefully; trim if purely procedural
    </handle_carefully>
    
    <not>
      - This is NOT a summary or condensation
      - This is NOT paraphrasing to simplify complex exchanges
      - This is NOT editorial rewriting to resolve disagreement or impose structure
      - This is NOT homogenizing distinct voices into panel uniformity
      - This is NOT removing the messiness that makes panel discussions valuable
      - This is NOT preserving commercial content or preview segments as part of the "authentic" conversation
    </not>
  </scope>

  <preview_content_detection>
    <what_are_previews>
      Preview content (also called "cold opens," "teasers," or "hooks") is material at the beginning of panel podcasts designed to entice listeners before the actual conversation begins. These segments:
      - Occur in the first 30-120 seconds before proper introductions
      - Pull exciting clips, disagreements, or reactions from later in the episode
      - Tease dramatic moments, debates, or revelations to come
      - Create artificial tension to prevent listener drop-off
      - Often feature music, sound effects, or different audio treatment
      - Break narrative continuity by jumping ahead then returning to the start
      - May feature panelists out of context making strong statements
    </what_are_previews>

    <recognition_patterns>
      Identify and remove preview segments containing:
      - Out-of-context exchanges or disagreements before proper introductions
      - Host statements like: "Coming up," "In this episode," "Today the panel discusses," "You'll hear," "Later in the show"
      - Teaser phrases: "Stay tuned for," "Don't miss," "We'll debate," "The panel weighs in on"
      - Decontextualized reactions or strong statements before conversation has established context
      - Audio from later segments played at the beginning
      - Cold opens that jump into mid-debate before proper setup
      - Episode premise descriptions before actual dialogue begins
      - Content that explicitly signals "this will happen later"
      - Music beds or production elements that frame preview content
      - Rapid-fire quote montages from panelists
      - Statements about what listeners "will hear" or what "the panel will discuss"
      - Dramatic disagreements pulled from later context
    </recognition_patterns>

    <removal_strategy>
      When preview content is detected:
      1. Remove entire preview segment completely
      2. Begin transcript at the natural conversation start (after introductions, after setup)
      3. Do NOT leave residue like "[preview removed]" or navigation text
      4. If preview bleeds into introduction, separate cleanly at the transition point
      5. Ensure conversation begins at its authentic starting point with proper panel setup
      6. If preview contains panelist exchanges that never appear later in full, they're lost (acceptable—previews use edited snippets)
      7. Trust that the panel conversation itself provides sufficient context without the preview
      
      IMPORTANT: Preview content exists solely for audience retention. Removing it doesn't harm the transcript—it restores the conversation's natural beginning where panelists are properly introduced and the discussion organically develops.
    </removal_strategy>

    <edge_cases>
      **Remove:**
      - All teaser clips regardless of how dramatic they are
      - Episode descriptions read by host before conversation begins
      - "What we'll debate today" summaries
      - Dramatic out-of-context exchanges used as hooks
      - Any content that explicitly references "later" or "coming up"
      - Preview montages showing each panelist making strong statements
      
      **Keep:**
      - Substantive introductions establishing who the panelists are
      - Host framing the topic in a way that provides necessary context
      - Brief setup of the panel format or special circumstances
      - Opening exchanges that are part of the natural conversation flow
      - Natural banter as panelists settle in (if substantive)
      
      **Judgment required:**
      - If host gives topic intro followed by genuine panel discussion: Keep intro if substantive framing, remove if pure teasing
      - If cold open is actually the beginning of the conversation (no jump forward): Keep it—it's not a preview
      - If first 2 minutes alternate between preview clips and intro: Remove preview clips, preserve introduction
      - If panelists are introduced mid-preview: Separate the introductions from the preview content
      
      The test: Does this content advance the panel conversation, or is it trying to retain the audience? If the latter, remove it.
    </edge_cases>

    <preview_vs_introduction>
      Distinguish between preview content and legitimate panel introductions:
      
      **Preview (REMOVE):**
      - "On today's show, the panel gets heated about..."
      - [Clip from minute 52] PANELIST_A: "That's absolutely absurd—" PANELIST_B: "No, you're missing the point—"
      - "Coming up, our panelists debate whether AI will..."
      - "You'll hear some surprising disagreements about..."
      - [Sound effect] [Music swell] [Dramatic exchange] [Music fade]
      - "The conversation gets intense when we discuss..."
      
      **Introduction (KEEP):**
      - "Welcome to the show. I'm your host, and I'm joined today by panelists A, B, and C."
      - "Before we start, let me introduce our panel..."
      - "Our topic today is AI safety. Let's begin with the basics."
      - Natural conversation opening: "Thanks for having us." "Great to be here with everyone."
      - Host setting ground rules or format: "We'll go around and each share initial thoughts."
      
      Previews are external marketing; introductions are part of the panel architecture. Keep the conversation, remove the marketing device.
    </preview_vs_introduction>
  </preview_content_detection>

  <commercial_content_detection>
    <recognition_patterns>
      Identify and remove segments containing:
      - Direct product/service endorsements with pricing or offers
      - Transition phrases: "speaking of which," "before we continue," "real quick," "this episode is brought to you"
      - Discount codes, URLs, or promotional deadlines
      - Host voice shift to "commercial register" (often more formal/scripted)
      - Descriptions of product features unrelated to podcast topic
      - Calls to action: "visit," "use code," "check out," "sign up"
      - Patreon/membership tier descriptions with benefits
      - References to "our sponsors," "today's sponsor," "this week's sponsor"
      - Podcast network promotional content
      - Merchandise descriptions (t-shirts, mugs, etc.)
    </recognition_patterns>

    <removal_strategy>
      When commercial content is detected:
      1. Remove entire segment cleanly without narrative residue
      2. Reconnect surrounding conversational threads naturally
      3. Preserve any genuine discussion that bookends the ad (rare but possible)
      4. Do NOT leave placeholder text like "[ad removed]" or "[sponsor read]"
      5. Ensure conversational flow appears unbroken
      6. If sponsor is referenced later in genuine discussion, keep those references
      
      IMPORTANT: Be aggressive with removal. The transcript should read as if commercial content never existed. Panel discussions often resume mid-thought after ads—reconstruct that continuity.
    </removal_strategy>

    <edge_cases>
      - If panelists joke about or reference a sponsor after the read: Keep the banter, remove the formal read
      - If a guest is promoting their own work that's central to discussion: Keep it (editorial judgment required)
      - If host says "we'll be right back" before break: Remove along with the return announcement
      - If panelists reference "our Patreon supporters" in genuine thank-you: Keep brief, remove detailed tier descriptions
      - If merchandise is discussed as related to podcast topic (e.g., design process): Keep the discussion, remove the sales pitch
    </edge_cases>
  </commercial_content_detection>

  <panel_dynamics>
    <speaker_constellation>
      Before transcribing, map the panel's social architecture:
      - **Host(s)**: Who steers conversation, asks questions, manages time
      - **Regular co-hosts**: Recurring voices with established rapport
      - **Guests**: External voices with specific expertise or perspective
      - **Power dynamics**: Who defers to whom, who interrupts whom
      - **Alliance patterns**: Which speakers naturally build on each other
      - **Contrast patterns**: Which speakers represent opposing viewpoints
      - **Conversational roles**: Who synthesizes, who provokes, who mediates, who provides examples
      
      Understanding this constellation helps preserve authentic group dynamics.
    </speaker_constellation>

    <multi_party_exchanges>
      Panel discussions create unique conversational patterns:
      
      **Three-way disagreements:**
      - Speaker A makes claim → B challenges → C offers third perspective
      - Preserve full sequence showing how panel navigates complexity
      - Use clear attribution to avoid reader confusion
      
      **Collaborative building:**
      - A introduces idea → B extends → C provides example → A refines
      - Keep entire chain showing collective thinking
      - Show how the idea evolves through multiple contributions
      
      **Group consensus:**
      - Multiple speakers agreeing simultaneously or in quick succession
      - Consolidate repetitive agreement but preserve the fact of collective endorsement
      - Note when entire panel aligns vs. when division persists
      
      **Conversational threading:**
      - Topic A being discussed → B raises Topic B → A and C finish A → Panel shifts to B
      - Maintain threads even when conversation temporarily fragments
      - Make topic transitions clear through paragraph breaks or brief connectors
      
      **Interruption cascades:**
      - A starts → B interrupts → C interrupts B → Group laughter → A continues
      - Simplify to essential dynamic without losing energy
      - Preserve if showing genuine disagreement or collaborative excitement
    </multi_party_exchanges>

    <role_specific_handling>
      **Host/Moderator:**
      - Keep question framing and topic introductions
      - Remove pure procedural elements ("let's take a quick break," "we're running long")
      - Preserve when synthesizing or challenging panelists
      - Remove time-keeping unless it's substantive ("we could talk about this for hours")
      
      **Co-hosts:**
      - Preserve banter and rapport-building that establishes group chemistry
      - Keep inside references if they illuminate group dynamic
      - Maintain distinct co-host voices (often more contrast than host/guest)
      
      **Guests:**
      - Preserve expertise signaling and credibility markers
      - Keep first-time setup ("I work on," "my background") minimal but present
      - Show how they navigate group they're not regular part of
      
      **Rotating panelists:**
      - If different guests each episode, ensure each voice is immediately distinguishable
      - Provide more explicit speaker identification if necessary
    </role_specific_handling>

    <conversational_architecture>
      Panel discussions have distinct structural patterns:
      
      **Round-robin contributions:**
      - Host asks question → Each panelist responds in sequence
      - Keep sequence intact to show range of perspectives
      - Note when one panelist's answer prompts another to revise theirs
      
      **Emergent debates:**
      - Two panelists begin disagreeing → Others choose sides or mediate
      - Preserve the evolution from casual discussion to structured debate
      - Show how alliances form and shift
      
      **Collaborative problem-solving:**
      - Panel collectively works through a question
      - Keep the messiness of multiple minds converging
      - Show false starts, corrections, and "yes-and" building
      
      **Topic fragmentation:**
      - Panel splinters into multiple simultaneous threads
      - Host attempts to wrangle or lets it play out
      - Preserve if showing authentic panel energy; simplify if creating confusion
    </conversational_architecture>
  </panel_dynamics>

  <methodology>
    <step_1_analyze>
      Read the entire transcript to identify:
      - Preview/teaser content at the beginning (first 1-3 minutes typically)
      - Number of panelists and their roles (host, co-hosts, guests)
      - Where the actual panel conversation begins (after preview and introduction)
      - Panel social architecture (power dynamics, alliances, contrasts)
      - Each speaker's distinctive voice markers
      - Conversational patterns (debate, collaboration, threading)
      - Commercial content segments (ads, sponsorships, promotions)
      - Load-bearing vs. decorative elements
      - Topic flow and how panelists hand off or compete for conversational space
    </step_1_analyze>

    <step_2_map_voices>
      For each panelist, map:
      - Distinctive vocabulary and rhetorical signature
      - Conversational role (synthesizer, provocateur, mediator, fact-provider)
      - Speech patterns (clipped/elaborate, formal/casual, assertive/tentative)
      - How they interrupt or build on others
      - Alliances and tensions with specific other panelists
      - Expertise markers and credibility signals
      
      Create profiles to ensure each voice remains distinct in final draft.
    </step_2_map_voices>

    <step_3_map_removable_content>
      Before drafting, identify all content to remove:
      - Mark preview content boundaries (usually at the very start)
      - Mark start/end points of ad reads and sponsorships
      - Note transition phrases into and out of commercial content
      - Identify any post-ad reconnection phrases
      - Plan how to reconnect panel threads after removal
      - Flag ambiguous cases (guest self-promotion, sponsor banter, intro vs. preview)
      
      This prevents accidentally preserving fragments in final draft.
    </step_3_map_removable_content>

    <step_4_draft>
      Compose in panel dialogue form, following conversational sequence:
      - Remove ALL identified preview and commercial content completely
      - Begin at the natural start of the panel conversation
      - Replace filler with clean speaker transitions
      - Use em-dashes (—) for interruptions and cross-talk
      - Keep each panelist's voice consistent and recognizable
      - Maintain panel dynamics (building, challenging, threading)
      - Preserve disagreements and how they unfold
      - Show collaborative thinking and consensus-building
      - Use paragraph breaks to manage complexity
      - Keep conversational threading clear
      - Preserve substantive tangents and exploratory moments
    </step_4_draft>

    <step_5_verify>
      For all terminology, proper names, product references, and factual claims:
      - Validate correct spelling and capitalization
      - Confirm current accuracy (company names, product releases)
      - Verify statistics or citations panelists mention
      - Check proper names of people, organizations, concepts
      - Note when panelists contradict each other on facts (preserve the contradiction, optionally footnote)
      
      VERIFICATION PROCESS:
      - Known/confident terminology → Pass through
      - Specialized/technical terms → Verify spelling and definition
      - Proper names → Validate capitalization and current status
      - Statistics/claims → Flag for user verification if uncertain
      - Panelist disagreements on facts → Note in footnotes
    </step_5_verify>

    <step_6_polish>
      Final refinements:
      - Read through for naturalness and panel energy
      - Verify preview removal is clean (does it start naturally with proper introductions?)
      - Confirm commercial removal is seamless
      - Check that each panelist remains distinct and recognizable
      - Ensure panel dynamics are visible (alliances, tensions, role differentiation)
      - Validate that conversational threading is clear
      - Confirm verification footnotes are accurate
      - Ensure the messiness of panel conversation is honored but followable
    </step_6_polish>
  </methodology>

  <artifact_format>
    <type>markdown</type>
    <structure>
      # [Podcast/Episode Title]
      
      **Host:** [Name]  
      **Panelists:** [Names]  
      **Context:** [Brief episode context if needed]
      
      ---
      
      [Natural panel conversation start—after preview and introduction]
      
      [Multi-voice panel dialogue with clear attribution]
      
      [Continues through to natural conclusion]
      
      ---
      
      *Note: All preview content, advertising, and promotional material has been removed from this transcript. The panel conversation begins at its natural starting point.*
      
      [Optional verification footnotes]
    </structure>
    
    <styling>
      - Speaker names in **bold** followed by colon
      - Em-dash (—) for interruptions or multi-speaker exchanges
      - *Italic* for emphasized words (sparingly, matching vocal stress)
      - Paragraph breaks between turns or when topic/dynamic shifts
      - Action beats when needed: "The panel laughed" or "Several speakers began talking at once"
      - No excessive formatting; panel dialogue needs clarity, not decoration
      - Footnotes [^1] for verification and clarifications
      - Consider brief section breaks (---) if panel explicitly shifts topics
    </styling>
  </artifact_format>

  <verification_footnotes>
    Include optional footnotes for:
    - Terminology clarification
    - Name/entity confirmation with brief context
    - Product references with current status
    - Statistical claims with notation of original source
    - Factual corrections if speaker misstates something material
    - Conflicting factual claims between panelists (note the conflict)
    - Ambiguous statements where meaning is unclear
    
    Format: [^1]: [Category]: [Verified information]
    Example: [^1]: **Conflict**: Sarah stated the product launched in 2023, but Marcus said 2024. Verified: October 2023.
    
    CRITICAL: Always preserve speakers' original claims. Use footnotes to provide context or note conflicts, not to editorially correct them. In panels, often another speaker will correct errors—preserve this dynamic rather than using footnotes.
  </verification_footnotes>

  <edge_cases>
    <ambiguous_commercial_content>
      Sometimes the line between content and commerce is blurry:
      
      **Remove:**
      - Detailed product feature descriptions with pricing
      - Any discount codes or promotional URLs
      - "Special offer for our listeners"
      - Detailed Patreon tier benefits
      
      **Keep (with judgment):**
      - Brief thank-you to supporters
      - Guest promoting work central to discussion topic
      - References to sponsors in organic banter post-ad
      - Panel discussing podcast itself as topic (meta-commentary)
      
      When in doubt, ask: "Is this advancing the intellectual conversation or selling something?" If the latter, remove it.
    </ambiguous_commercial_content>

    <host_managing_panel>
      Host procedural statements require judgment:
      
      **Remove:**
      - "We need to take a break"
      - "We're running long"
      - "Let's move on to questions"
      - Time-keeping announcements
      
      **Keep:**
      - "This could be its own three-hour episode" (if substantive commentary)
      - "We're all talking over each other" (if noting panel dynamic)
      - "Let's hear from [quiet panelist]" (if redistributing conversational space)
      - Topic introductions and transitions
      
      Host's steering is part of panel architecture—keep when substantive, remove when purely procedural.
    </host_managing_panel>

    <guest_self_promotion>
      Guests often mention their work:
      
      **Keep:**
      - Work directly relevant to discussion topic
      - References that establish expertise or credibility
      - Brief mentions in context of explaining their perspective
      
      **Remove:**
      - Detailed "where to find me" segments
      - Sales pitches for books/courses/products
      - URLs and handles (unless organically part of discussion)
      
      If the guest's work IS the topic, keep more. If it's tangential promotional content, remove it.
    </guest_self_promotion>

    <post_ad_reconnection>
      After removing ads, conversational threads must reconnect seamlessly:
      
      **Before ad removal:**
      SPEAKER_A: So I think the real issue is—
      [AD READ]
      HOST: So as you were saying about the real issue...
      SPEAKER_A: Right, the real issue is funding.
      
      **After ad removal:**
      **SPEAKER_A:** So I think the real issue is funding.
      
      Remove both the ad AND the reconnection phrase. The transcript should read as if no interruption occurred. This requires understanding the conversational thread to reconnect it properly.
    </post_ad_reconnection>

    <complex_multi_party_exchanges>
      Sometimes panel dynamics are genuinely complex:
      - Three simultaneous disagreements
      - Four people building an idea together
      - Topic threading across six speakers
      
      In these cases:
      - Prioritize clarity over preserving every utterance
      - Use paragraph breaks liberally
      - Consider brief editorial connectors if necessary ("The panel debated three aspects...")
      - Simplify crosstalk without losing essential content
      - Trust reader to follow complex exchanges if well-attributed
      
      Panel conversations can be messy—honor that messiness, but make it followable.
    </complex_multi_party_exchanges>
  </edge_cases>

  <quality_checklist>
    [ ] ALL preview/teaser content completely removed
    [ ] Transcript begins at natural panel conversation start with proper introductions
    [ ] ALL advertising and sponsorship content completely removed
    [ ] Commercial content removal is seamless (no narrative residue)
    [ ] Post-ad reconnections handled cleanly
    [ ] Filler words and tics systematically removed per speaker
    [ ] Each speaker's voice remains distinctive and immediately recognizable
    [ ] Co-hosts are clearly differentiated (not interchangeable)
    [ ] Panel dynamics preserved (building, challenging, threading)
    [ ] Multi-party disagreements remain intact and clear
    [ ] Interruptions and cross-talk handled thoughtfully
    [ ] Topic threading across speakers is coherent
    [ ] Role differentiation visible (host, co-hosts, guests)
    [ ] Group energy and rhythm preserved
    [ ] Alliances and tensions authentically maintained
    [ ] Consensus-building visible where it occurs
    [ ] Conversational messiness honored but made followable
    [ ] Meta-commentary about panel kept when substantive
    [ ] Terminology verified for accuracy
    [ ] Proper names capitalized correctly
    [ ] Product references (non-ad) current and accurate
    [ ] Statistical claims flagged or verified
    [ ] Speaker attribution always clear
    [ ] Paragraph breaks follow conversational flow and manage complexity
    [ ] Verification footnotes included where helpful
    [ ] No editorial rewriting or homogenization
    [ ] Readability elevated without sacrificing panel authenticity
    [ ] Transcript flows as if preview and commercial content never existed
  </quality_checklist>

  <input_format>
    Provide the podcast transcript as:
    [PASTE TRANSCRIPT HERE]
    
    Optionally include:
    - Podcast/episode title
    - Panelist names and roles (if not obvious from transcript)
    - Podcast URL or release date
    - Any special terminology to prioritize verification
    - Context about panel composition or discussion focus
    - Note if certain speakers are particularly difficult to distinguish
  </input_format>

  <output_delivery>
    Return as a markdown artifact containing:
    1. Polished multi-voice panel dialogue narrative
    2. Complete panelist identification and metadata
    3. Note confirming all preview and commercial content removed
    4. Optional verification footnotes
    5. Brief note (if needed) on ambiguities, unclear sections, or substantive editorial decisions
    
    The final transcript should read as a professional, engaging multi-party conversation that begins naturally and is free from commercial interruption and audience-retention devices.
  </output_delivery>
</prompt>
